Guide to the E. Ethelbert Miller papers, 1936-2021, bulk 1962-2018 MS2215
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Ethelbert Miller materials, 1962-2018; 1940-2021; Series 1; Miller, E. Ethelbert
  - Personal materials, circa 1940-2020; circa 1980s-2010s; Series 1 Subseries 9
    - Miller Children and Family materials, 1965, 1979, 1991, 2004, 2019, 2020, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 4)
    - Personal items and newsclippings [1/2], circa 1980s-1990s; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 5)
    - Personal items and newsclippings [2/2], circa 1980s-1990s; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 6)
    - Personal Materials, 1979, 2000; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 7)
    - "The Hilltop," Howard University, 1968 November; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 8)
    - Journals, 2020; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, 1951, 1983, 1997, 2000, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, 1987, 1991, 199, 2003, 2007, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 11)
    - Photographs and other materials, 1978, 1979, 1983, 1987, 1991, 1992, 1997, 1998, 2000, 2002, 2003, 2005, 2006, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 12)
    - St. John's College Writing Intensive, 2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 13)
    - Ta-Neihisi Coates - Photos Lincoln Theater 2019, MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 206, Folder 14)
    - Notebook, 2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 1)
    - Planner, 2018; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 2)
    - 2019 Planner, MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 3)
    - Weekly Planner Pages: March 4, 2019-November 15, 2019, 2019 March 4-2019 November 15, 2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 4)
    - E-70 Project [E. Ethelbert Miller's 70th Birthday Celebration], 2020, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 5)
    - Ethelbert Miller's 70th Birthday, 2020; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 207, Folder 6)
    - Cap: "H" (Howard University), circa 1968; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Item 1)
    - Hat: "GXP" (Gamma Xi Phi), undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Item 2)
      "Gamma Xi Phi is a predominately African American organization of men and women in the arts, including literature, visual art, music, theater, and dance."--from the Gamma Xi Phi website, 2021
    - Hat: "The Scholars with E. Ethelbert Miller", undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Item 3)
    - Tote Bag: Literary Hill BookFest, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Item 4)
    - Tote Bag: 10th Gaithersburg Book Festival, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Item 5)
    - Theater Programs, 1965, 1992, 2005; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 9 (Box 215, Folder 1)
    - Campaign, Organization, Commemorative, and Photo buttons, 1981, 1995, 2008, 2009, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Suberies 9 (Box 215, Folder 2)
  - Organizations, 1981-2020; Series 1 Subseries 10
    Arranged alphabetically.
    This subseries contains materials related to various organizations that Miller was associated with. The materials date from 1981-2020.
    - Organizations, 1989-1991; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: American Writers Congress (1/3), 1981-1983; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: American Writers Congress (2/3), 1981-1983; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: American Writers Congress (3/3), 1981; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: Annie Sprinkle, 1990 February; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: The Arts Club of Washington, 1993-1995; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: Associated Writing Programs, Old Dominion University, 1993; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs][1/2], 1991 June-1992 March; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [2/2], 1991-1993; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [1/5], 1989-1990; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [2/5], 1990 February- May; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [3/5], 1990 May-October; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [4/5], 1990 November-1991 February; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: AWP [Associated Writing Programs] [5/5], 1991 March-May; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Board Membership, 1986-2013; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: Board Membership, 1980-1995; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1985-1993; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 1997; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: Edmond Burke School, 1997 June 27; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: Frohnmayer NEA Chairman, 1990-1992; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), 1990-1995; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), 1996; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS), 1997, 2006-2008, 2013; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Ideas Into Action, 2006; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Reports and Articles, 2007-2008; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Minutes, 2006-2007; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Personal, 2004-2005; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Communications, 2004-2009; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Board, 2006-2007; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Salon, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Salsa, 2004; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Miscellaneous, 2004-2008; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Budget, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Long Range Committee, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - Organizations: Institute for Policy Studies (IPS) Annual Report, 2012; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Organizations: Literacy Volunteers of America National Capital Area, 1998; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: PEN American Center, 1987-1994; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: PEN/Faulkner Foundation, 1988-1993; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: National Association of Third World Writers, 1980-1982; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: National Writers Union, 1985-1986, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts], 1991-1995; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [1/11], 1990 August; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [2/11], 1990 September-November; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 5)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [3/11], 1990 November-December; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [4/11], 1991 January-March; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [5/11], 1991 April-June; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 8)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [6/11], 1990-1991; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 9)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [7/11], 1989-1991; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [8/11], 1993-1995; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 167, Folder 11)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [9/11], 1993 June 30; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [10/11], 1993 September 8-1995 January 16; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [11/11], 1994 March 2; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [1/5], 1990-1994; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [2/5], 1987-1991; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [3/5], 1990 May-1991 May; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [4/5], 1990 June; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 9)
    - Organizations: NEA [National Endowment for the Arts] [5/5], 1990 July; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 10)
    - Organizations: Pin Points Theatre, 1984-1991; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Robert Mapplethorpe, 1989-1990; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Organizations: Washington Area Lawyers for the Arts (WALA), 1997-1998; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - National Book Festival, 2001-2003; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Folger Poetry, 2002-2003; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - March on Washington Film Festival, 2017; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald Literary Festival, 2017; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 4)
    - Women's National Democratic Club, 2017; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - Institute for Policy Studies, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - D.C. Literary Archive, 2000; Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 192, Folder 7)
    - F. Scott Fitzgerald Literary Festival, 2016 and 2019, 2016, 2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 207, Folder 7)
    - Gaithersburg Book Festival, May 18, 2019, MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 207, Folder 8)
    - The History Makers, 2001, 2003, 2005, 2009, 2020; Ms2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 207, Folder 9)
    - National Book Festival programs, 2001, 2003; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 207, Folder 10)
    - National Book Festival Poetry Pavilion, 2003; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 207, Folder 11)
    - Various Poetry-related Organizations, 2018-2020, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 208, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Center for the Creative Arts Summer 2019 Residency, 2018-2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 208, Folder 2)
    - Washington, DC Hall of Fame Society, Inc. - 15th Annual Hall of Fame Awards Program, 2015 April 19; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 208, Folder 3)
    - The Writer's Center, "The Writer's Guide" Summer 2019, MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 208, Folder 4)
    - Wyoming Arts Council, 2018-2019; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 10 (Box 208, Folder 5)
  - Audiovisual materials, 1985-2015; Series 1 Subseries 11
    This subseries contains video cassettes, CDs, and DVDs related to E. Ethelbert Miller's professional activities. The materials date from 1985-2015.
    - American Accents CD, 2010; Series 1 Subseries11 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - An Evening with Dr. Stephen E. Henderson Videocassette (1/3), 21 November 1985; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 166, Item 1)
    - An Evening with Dr. Stephen E. Henderson Videocassette, 21 November 1985; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 166, Item 2)
    - An Evening with Dr. Stephen E. Henderson Videocassette (3/3), 21 November 1985; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 166, Item 3)
    - Audio and videocassettes, undated; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 156)
    - Audio and videocassettes, undated; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 157)
    - Audio and videocassettes, undated; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 158)
    - Audio and videocassettes, undated; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 159)
    - David's Poetry Tape, undated; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 5)
    - E. Ethelbert Miller - WPFW, 1998; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 3)
    - E. Ethelbert Miller hosts Edward P. Jones, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - E. Ethelbert Miller "Project 60" Gelman Library GWU Parts 1 and 2 [1/2], 2010 November 19; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 208, Folder 6)
    - E. Ethelbert Miller "Project 60" Gelman Library GWU Parts 3 and 4 [2/2], 2010 November 19; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 208, Folder 7)
    - Ethelbert, undated; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 6)
    - Ethelbert and Miyuhi, 2005; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 4)
    - Ethelbert Miller Hosts David Mura DVD, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 166, Item 4)
    - Furious Flower III Video Anthology, 2015 July 29; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - HoCoPoLitSco "The Writing Life: E. Ethelbert Miller and Sekou Sundiata", 2000 June 23; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 208, Folder 8)
    - HoCoPoLitSco "The Writing Life: Henry Taylor hosts the 1st Poetry Quartet" (Henry Taylor, E. Ethelbert Miller, Anna Dar, Hillary Tham), 1994 December 9; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 208, Folder 9)
    - HoCoPoLitSco "The Writing Life: Michael Collier with poet E. Ethelbert Miller", 1996 November 25; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 209, Folder 1)
    - Irv Berlin (camera 1) w TC, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 209, Folder 2)
    - Michael Collier with poet E. Ethelbert Miller, 1987; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 190, Folder 3)
    - Muse to Muse guest Wendy Reigger, 2005 August 27; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 199, Folder 4, Videocassette 1)
    - Richard Miller and Juanita Faulkner, 1981 June; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 199, Folder 16, Cassette 1)
    - The Poet and The Poem from the Library of Congress, series 1 subersies 11 (Box 186, Item 1)
    - Speaking of Faith: Black and Universal-Meeting E. Ethelbert Miller CD, 2010 February 11; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - The Bob Edwards Show, Jim Guest & E. Ethelbert Miller, 2005 June 23; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 209, Folder 3)
    - Various CDs, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Various CDs, 2003, 2004, 2006, undated; MS2215 Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 209, Folder 4)
    - The Writer's Forum, 1999; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 2)
    - The Writing Life, 2013; series 1 subseries 11 (Box 186, Item 7)
    - 16 Poems of Sterling A. Brown, 1992; Series 1 Subseries 11 (Box 190, Folder 5)
- Dolores Kendrick materials, Series 2; .5 linear feet
  This series contains material amassed by E. Ethelbert Miller relating to the work of poet Dolores Kendrick.
  - Correspondence, Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Profiles: newspapers and magazines, Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, flyers, Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous materials, Series 2 (Box 18, Folder 4)